Athens, GA, 30605 USA

# Kushajveer Singh

(706) 461-9944 kushajreal@gmail.com kushajveersingh.com

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Full-stack developer experienced with creating fully-responsive mobile first web applications and doing API integrations, reading documentation to add new features to an existing codebase, code review processes, CI/CD testing. Self-motivated and passionate to learn new technologies and build projects on top of it. Experienced with deploying more than 6 projects on Vercel/Heroku, contributing to open-source projects on GitHub for over 5 years, and maintaining a technical blog with 16 published posts.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Georgia, Franklin College of Arts & Sciences Master of Science in Computer Science (GPA: 3.82/4.00) Athens, GA, USA

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

# Punjab Engineering College (Deemed to be University)

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering (CGPA: 7.0/10.0)

Chandigarh, India Aug 2016 – Jun 2020

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- C, C++, Python, PyTorch, Git, GitHub, Circle CI, Docker, Shell Scripting, Web Scraping, Agile (Scrum), Linux
- HTML, CSS (BEM), Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Next.js, Redux, Material UI, Stripe, Twilio, Bcrypt, OAuth, Sanity, Jest, Node.js, Express, Django, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Full Stack Developer** 

Athens, GA, USA

Jul 2022 - current

- College of Agriculture and Environmental Sciences, UGA
  - Implemented Node.js/Express parser to do real time Microsoft Access to PostgreSQL query conversion
    Brought up development and production servers, including IP whitelisting and backup configuration with periodic syncing, and migrated 18 years of data from Access to PostgreSQL database
  - Automated data entry pipeline using Python/TypeScript, resulting in a reduction of time from 2 minutes per handwritten form to 25 seconds on average, by implementing autocomplete functionality for various fields
  - Rewrote the entire codebase for a proprietary language, which included converting information from a 200-page manual to a TypeScript/Next.js application and updating the queries from Access to PostgreSQL

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

Athens, GA, USA

Computer Science Department, UGA

Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

- Led weekly meetings and facilitated group discussions for the course Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science
- Held one-on-one office hours for 2 transfer students, covering the entire course in detail while covering practical applications of the content and mentored students on the career paths in computer science

#### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Google CS Research Mentorship Program**

Student

Athens, GA, USA (Remote)

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

Selected for a 12-week Google Research program among 50 candidates from across USA and Canada

#### Winner TechGig CodeGladiators

Punjab, India

Hackathon

May 2019 – Jul 2019

- Won the first solo place in Artificial Intelligence hackathon where 15 teams were selected from across India from a pool of about 0.6 million candidates
- Built a fully deployable and unsupervised parking space detection system using PyTorch and OpenCV
- Ability to adjust predictions based on where cars are parked over time

# Third place North-Zone IndiaSkills Nationals

Chandigarh, India

IT Software Solutions for Business

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018

Built desktop application using C# and android application using Java to win third place at IndiaSkills nationals

Both applications fetched data from a MySQL and phpMyAdmin database setup

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

### YouTube Video Platform | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Material-UI web app using YouTube API and deployed on Vercel
- Implemented video section, category section, responsive channel and video cards, channel pages, video pages with ability to play videos straight from the app and see related videos

#### Video Sharing App | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive full-stack video sharing social media app using React/Next.js/TypeScript/Tailwind CSS/ Zustand/Sanity and deployed on Vercel
- Google auth to register and login user, ability to upload, publish, share, comment on and like the videos
- Advanced search functionalities, filter by categories, profile pages, and see suggested accounts

### Chat Messaging App | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive full-stack chat messaging application using React/TypeScript/Bcrypt and Stream Chat API
- Support for authentication, Twilio SMS notification, direct and group chats, emojis and reactions, GIF support
- Deployed React frontend on Vercel, and deployed Express.is backend on Heroku

### **Ecommerce Website | GITHUB, DEMO**

- Built full-responsive and scalable modern ecommerce website using Next.js/TypeScript and deployed on Vercel
- Used Next.js as backend endpoint, Stripe for managing payments, shipping rates and entire checkout process
- Manage entire content of website using Sanity, change details of products or add new products on the go

### Music Player and Discovery App | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive modern music player app using React/Next.js/Tailwind CSS/TypeScript/Redux/Shazam API
- Choose genre and view top songs, see top charts and artists for the country or worldwide
- Music player with controls to go to next/previous song, repeat, shuffle, fast forward, adjust volume
- Fully functional search and pages to explore most popular songs in the country, using IP Geolocation API
- View song's lyrics and official video, related songs, and other songs by the artist

#### **Group Video Chat | GITHUB, DEMO**

- Built group video chat app using JavaScript/Agora, and deployed the backend on Heroku and frontend on Vercel
- Conference chat with multiple people at same time, screen share, private/group messaging, admin controls, polls
- Worked with an enterprise scale codebase and added features on top of it by reading documentation

#### Restaurant Website | GITHUB, DEMO

- Converted Figma design into fully-responsive Next.js/TypeScript/CSS(BEM) web app and deployed on Vercel
- Modern UI/UX website built using CSS Flexbox/Grid, animations, and gradients

#### Pathfinding Visualizer | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Redux web app for visualizing pathfinding algorithms, mazegeneration algorithms deployed on Vercel
- Implemented 9 different algorithms and added random weight generation methods to visualize weighted shortest cost algorithms

### Sort Visualizer | GITHUB, DEMO

- Deployed fully-responsive React/Next.js/TypeScript/Redux web app for visualizing sorting algorithms on Vercel
- Implemented over 30 sorting algorithms, view multiple algorithms in parallel, generate 4 types of random array

### JSON/YAML Graph Visualizer | GITHUB, DEMO

- Built React/Next.js/Redux/Material-UI web app to convert JSON/YAML data into graph for improved readability
- Wrote YAML to JSON parser in TypeScript

### **Bookstore application | GITHUB**

- Built full-stack bookstore application using HTML/CSS/JavaScript for frontend and Django/SQLite for backend
- Implemented user authentication with email, change/forgot password, edit profile, advanced search options, cart management, apply promotions, entire process for placing an order